<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>slers blog (wordpress)</title><link>http://slers68.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://slers68.github.io/categories/wordpress.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 23:00:51 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>What about wordpress?</title><link>http://slers68.github.io/posts/what-about-wordpress.html</link><dc:creator>slers68</dc:creator><description>Getting rid of wordpress felt good for several reasons:
Security
Ok, this one is so obvious and you can not really compare a live rendered page with user managment and all kind of built in stuff to serving a static site. But what is comparable is the amount of time you spend to keep up with security of wordpress. And this is of course a lot more than just making the updates (god, I don't know how outdated installations I found till this date). I remember, not long ago there was an issue (or still is) with the pingbacks, to use it of a way to make a ddos-attack. Gladly my wordpress site never had those enabled.
I don't have to update my static site generator ever. And because this is not running on my own web server I don't have to care about its security either.
Spam
Ok, again a point that is a bit unfair (I could have disabled the comment form easily in wordpress) but by not having an integrated commenting system it is just one less thing to think about. Plus notifications are a problem here and the crap gets saved. I had email notifications, but deleting about 2000 spam mails a day just is no fun. There would have been methods to stop those, I am sure, but this is extra stuff I have to handle in my - at least at the moment - limited spare time.
PS: For comments just send a mail to slers@incognitomail.org which is just an RSS-Feed for me, very handy!
I don't wanna care!
Really. I don't. I want a system that runs (that is why I don't have my own web server). I can not count on wordpress for that matter. Especially wordpress is targeted more and more. This is not wordpress fault, but the amount of insecurities discovered is not speaking for the software.</description><category>self</category><category>wordpress</category><guid>http://slers68.github.io/posts/what-about-wordpress.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 12:48:09 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>